what's going on ladies and gentlemen
welcome back to another one and in this
video we're going to be doing another
review on one of my more recent
purchases I've made we're going to be
reviewing the Abu Garcia Max X and I
tell you what this thing is super cool
the uh Abu Garcia Maxx it's one of their
more budget-friendly bait casters you
can buy these things for right around 70
80 bucks maybe a little bit cheaper if
you find it on sale and uh they're
pretty cool it's a seven foot medium
heavy rod and you get the combo with it
so you get the you get the Reel as well
so for 80 bucks I thought why not give
it a try and give you guys a little
review on it and see what we think so
we're going to jump into it we're out on
the kayak today hoping that we can catch
some fish and the wind kind of picked up
so we got a little bit wet on our way
out here but nothing that's going to
stop us so let's jump into it so as we
start to break this thing down and talk
about it
um we're gonna start with the Reel now
the Reel has a black and red finish
which I think looks really nice the
grips on it feel pretty good you know
they feel a little bit cheaper than like
your higher end bait casters but not too
bad it's super super smooth when you
reel it in so there's no issues there it
does feel like mostly a plastic body the
crank is obviously a metal and you do
have some more plastic up top here but
the main components are you know seem to
be made with pretty good quality stuff I
just don't know how long the outside
will last if you bang it up on stuff and
everything like that but it seems to be
all around not too bad it has five
bearings in it which is you know pretty
reasonable I wouldn't say it's bad or
like super super good but it gets the
job done and that's kind of what we're
looking for in a budget setup along with
that it has a 641 gear ratio and it'll
actually reel in 25 inches of line per
turn per crank with your with your reel
here so for each Crank that you give it
is 25 inches which is kind of a lot I
feel like you could get away with using
crankbaits and just about anything like
that with it so all around I don't have
anything really bad to say about the
Reel I have a 12 pound monofilament on
here here and it seems to be casting
pretty nice I would definitely recommend
turning those brakes up to start because
when I first got it I had the brakes all
the way down and I was casting and I did
get a couple bird's nests nothing
horrible I was able to get them out in
just a minute or two
but that did happen and once the brakes
were turned up a little bit I didn't
have any issues all around I do really
like the Reel I think it has a really
slick presentation I think it looks
really nice with the black and red
finish on the Reel and you get a little
bit of the gray into the red
um obviously this would be like your
cheaper version of like the Abu Garcia
Max Pro and if you guys do want to check
out that video I'll link it to in the
top here because I did do a review on
that one and that is a really super cool
bait caster as well but there's a lot of
similarities here it doesn't seem like
they really chinsed out on anything the
rod is super nice there's a little grip
here I feel like this could be a little
bit bigger just to kind of hold on to
but all around not too bad with it being
that seven foot you know medium heavy
Rod it definitely gets the job done you
know I like a longer Rod I think I've
stated in other videos but seven foot is
more than enough and like I said
especially when you're looking at like
budget setups I don't know if I have a
weed or a fish nope I had a weed when
you're looking at budget setups you
can't be too picky on like the length of
your rod and that kind of thing but the
action is super important and I feel
like the medium heavy action is
definitely sufficient here you could
handle just about anything with a medium
heavy rod and that's actually what I
like to run with most of my bait casters
so I wouldn't change anything about that
you do have the nice handle this little
handle here is rubber kind of has some
nice grips on it and it feels good and
then you do have your hook holder right
here I don't I'm not a huge fan of this
actually and I don't know why they do it
like this maybe it's for like speed or
something like that so that you can hook
your you know put your hook on it really
fast but it's really hard to get the
hook in there so most of the time what
I've been doing is just setting it like
that and then cranking it in so it's not
actually in that Loop which is okay just
a little bit different I do have a
couple of rods like that but not my not
my favorite but all in all not bad
um it's got a really nice finish to it
it goes from this like kind of graphic
looking red to just plain red and it
looks really really good there's nine
eyelets to the rod which is more than
sufficient you get to the end and
they're really really small which really
helps with your accuracy and you can
really rip this thing out there I'm
throwing a senko with just a little egg
weight on it and uh it casts really good
I'm actually really surprised as to how
good this thing casts like I said I've
had a couple of backlashes but nothing
too bad honestly
um I would say though for me personally
one of my biggest cons to this reel is
that you cannot buy this reel in a
left-handed reel okay they don't make it
I looked everywhere I looked on Abu
Garcia's website and I think it's mostly
just because of the budget you know
friendly setup that it is is you have to
get this in the right-handed reel which
is okay typically I like to use my bait
casters with my left hand but I don't
really have any problems switching over
because I do cast with my right hand
like this and then I just switch over so
if you do a real left-handed like me you
can probably make it work but I do kind
of wish that this was over here just for
Simplicity
um and just fishing with what I'm used
to but it's not too big a deal all
around right now I have these brakes at
about halfway I'm going to cast this
thing out as hard as I can and see what
happens I'm kind of expecting a bird's
nest but we'll see
no bird's nest I probably could have
casted a little bit harder but
it definitely got the job done we'll
give it another try here let me crank it
in all right here we go we're gonna give
this guy the hardest cast yet
wow I have to say that's pretty
impressive for a rather new fishing pole
especially a bait caster I didn't put my
thumb on that at all and there's no
bird's nest that is pretty sweet that
makes me like this a lot more because
that can be pretty hard to find in a
bait caster now if you threw braid on it
it could be a little bit different
it definitely could bird's nest with
some braid on it I don't really ever
expect you know your cheap bait casting
setup to you know cast as far as your
higher end stuff but all in all it does
seem to be pretty good I think it's
going to stand the test of time it seems
like they didn't put two cheaper
components on here I would say the
outside of the Reel would be the only
thing that would concern me for the
price you really can't beat it you're
getting a lot of like higher end looking
stuff the rod is definitely something to
write home about the rod seems to hold
up really really well there's really
good sensitivity at the tip and and all
in all seems to be a really good setup I
would say if you guys are looking for a
cheap bait casting setup you really can
never go wrong with Abu Garcia and the
Abu Garcia Max X has definitely met my
expectations if you guys enjoyed this
video make sure you subscribe to the
channel and we'll see you in the next
one peace